Dr. Po-Hsun Tseng (曾柏勳)

6+ years experience of large-scale software development with C programming on the Linux system throughout my Ph.D. journey. Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity with low-level system programming (eg. device driver, Linux kernel, CPU architecture) to apply my skills at a fabless company.



CONTACT

zengbs@gmail.com

+886 966 587 832

Hsinchu, Taiwan

https://github.com/zengbs

SKILLS

Programming

C
Bash scripting
System programming
CUDA
Python



Operating System

Linux - user Linux - kernel



Architecture

ARM architecture



Software & Tools

Git Vim Gdb Valgrind



Languages

Chinese (native) English



EDUCATION

Ph.D. in Computational Physics

National Taiwan University, Taiwan

1 08/2016 - 06/2022

- Developed a new algorithm in C to reduce numerical error by 10^6 compared to conventional algorithm. Published in *Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society* 2021 Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315
- Designed a new approach to further promote the robustness of our program (GAMER) for research. The new approach was adopted in the research project led by Dr. Kuo-Chuan Pan from Tsing Hua University.

(https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/pull/60)

- Improved the GAMER collaborated with Dr. Tzihong Chiueh and Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive. See the Section *References*.
- A main contributor of the GAMER.
 (https://github.com/gamer-project/gamer/graphs/contributors)
- Built NIS, NFS, and Linux cluster from scratch with colleagues and worked with Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive to bootstrap simulations for research.

WORK HISTORY

Circuit designer

♀ TDK corporation, Singapore

01/2015 - 02/2016

• Designed the circiut of surface acoustic wave (SAW) filters

Military service

1 08/2013 - 08/2014

EDUCATION

M.Sc. in Physics

♀ National Taiwan University, Taiwan

09/2011 - 07/2013

B.Sc. in Mathematics

1 09/2006 - 07/2011

GENERAL SKILLS

Numerical algorithm

Large-scale project

cscope

makefile

GNU autotools

PUBLICATIONS

- [1] An adaptive mesh, GPU-accelerated, and error minimized special relativistic hydrodynamics code
- Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsi-Yu Schive, Tzihong Chiueh
- Monthly Notices of the Royal Astronomical Society 2021 Vol. 504, pp. 3298-3315
- https://doi.org/10.1093/mnras/stab1006
- [2] The symmetry problem of the Fermi and eROSITA bubbles: A proof-of-concept study
- Po-Hsun Tseng, Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang, Hsi-Yu Schive, Chun-Yen Chen, Tzihong Chiueh
- preprint 2022

TALKS

- An adaptive-mesh, GPU-accelerated, and optimally error-controlled special relativistic hydrodynamics code
 Oral (remote), American Center for Physics College Park, U.S.A
 Mar. 2021
- A new and accurate code for simulating special relativistic hydrodynamics Oral, Annual Meeting of the Physical Society of Taiwan, NPTU.

Feb. 2020

REFERENCES

- Please send an appointment letter to request a call. $\stackrel{\square}{=}$
- Dr. Tzihong Chiueh
 Distinguished Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University
 - ▼ Taipei 10617, Taiwan
 - chiuehth@phys.ntu.edu.tw
 - +886 2 3366 8628
- Dr. Hsi-Yu Schive

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astrophysics, National Taiwan University

- Taipei 10617, Taiwan
- hyschive@phys.ntu.edu.tw
- **** +886 2 3366 8644
- Dr. Hsiang-Yi Karen Yang

Assistant Professor, Institute of Astronomy, National Tsing Hua University

- Hsinchu 30013, Taiwan
- hyang@phys.nthu.edu.tw
- **4886 3 574 2953**